Hello, my name is Lachina Robinson and I'm a sports broadcaster for ESPN.
I am so excited to be joining Melissa Dawn-Simkins and the Velvet Suite as a founding ambassador
for athleadership.
You're probably wondering what a basketball analyst has in common with business leaders.
When I say the word agility, I hope that resonates with you because it definitely resonates with
me and I will tell you how.
As a basketball analyst, it is my job to be the expert on the broadcast.
Leading up to a game, I spend countless hours watching film, interviewing players and coaches,
studying statistics, diving into the rules of the game, learning every aspect of the
entire event.
My specific function as the color on the broadcast is to explain and analyze why things
are happening.
Why does player A have 30 points?
Why is team B in a zone defense?
Why did coach A just call a timeout?
What does it mean when the officials call travel?
I am teaching by taking the viewer behind the veil into the minds of the players, coaches,
officials, even the fans, to explain why certain events are taking place and hopefully
make the game more enjoyable.
The definition of agility is the ability to think and understand quickly.
There are hundreds of thousands and sometimes millions of people watching a sporting event
on television at any given time.
And it's my job to understand what is happening very quickly and to be able to communicate
that to the audience in the moment as it's happening.
Talk about pressure, but you get it because it is essential that you are equipped with
this tool as a business leader.
Let me give you an example of how agility comes into play in my day to day.
In that high pressure situation with millions of viewers watching a game, I have prepared
for what I expect to happen in the game.
Sure, nothing in sports ever happens the way we expect, but that doesn't change my role.
And that is where agility comes in.
As a leader, we can prepare for the moment and do the diligence required to be an expert,
but nothing can prepare you for the moment of having to change course under pressure.
To communicate to an audience, to your staff, to those who follow your command that something
else is happening, something I didn't specifically prepare for, but I couldn't predict it.
However, because I have trained, I know that I can find my way and make the changes necessary.
Agility takes trust that as an expert, you prepared for a change of plans, that the unexpected
outcome or action isn't the end of your skill set or training.
You don't know how your opponent will game plan for you, but you know that whatever that
looks like, you can think and understand quickly in order to adjust.
You can be agile in reaching your goal, even if you get there in a different way than you expected.
Being agile is critical in situations where you need to adjust.
I hope this helps you in your journey as an athlete.
You have everything you need.
You have prepared, practiced, and now it's time to execute.
Stay agile.